Hi. I'm David Hill with New York Habitat.
Welcome to another New York Habitat video tour of London.
Today we will be exploring Canary Wharf and Docklands.
Canary Wharf is one of the two main financial centres in London
alongside the City of London.
Nearly 100,000 people work in Canary Wharf
and it is home to some of the UK's tallest buildings,
housing some of the world's major financial and media organisations.
Canary Wharf and the Docklands area are in the east of London
focussing on the Isle of Dogs.
North of the River Thames this runs from Limehouse in the East
to London City Airport in the West.
Cabot Square, named after the Italian explorer
is one of the central squares in the heart of Canary Wharf
next to the Canary Wharf DLR station.
Home to several renowned investment and retail banks
it is a thriving metropolis with several restaurants
and a large shopping centre.
West India Quay is a stone's throw from Cabot Square.
Since its heyday as a major quay involved in shipping goods
such as tea, sugar, and rum, it has undergone major development.
With the London Docks no longer in operation
West India Quay has retained some of its historic charm on the outside
but now provides residential housing, hotels,
and restaurants for the Canary Wharf locals.
Telling the story of the river Thames,
the Museum of London Docklands is a fascinating historical journey
starting with the Roman settlement in AD43
through to the modern day development
with some wonderful galleries.
New York Habitat has a number of apartment opportunities
in the Canary Wharf and Docklands area.
Renowned for its modern wharf-side developments
why not check out nyhabitat.com
to find some of these hidden gems.
At the south end of the Isle of Dogs,
Island Gardens has some fantastic views across the river.
Looking across, you will catch views of Greenwich Hospital,
National Maritime Museum, and the Cutty Sark.
Did you know you could walk under the river Thames?!
This tunnel beneath the river has been open since 1902!
Built to replace an unreliable ferry service,
this 370 metre tunnel will take you from Island Gardens
to the south side of the river
near to the Cutty Sark in Greenwich.
In the 18th century
the River Thames was drained and development started.
As a tidal river it was at risk of flooding
but the Thames Barrier, completed in 1984, now protects the city.
London's most central airport is right here in Docklands.
Opened in 1988 it has become a trans-Atlantic hub
seeing more than 3 million passengers per year.
There are a number of ways of travelling to and from
Canary Wharf and Docklands.
There is the Thames Clipper water-bus service.
The Jubilee line of the London underground.
And the popular and fully automated Docklands Light Railway (or DLR).
This is Canary Wharf.
With over 240 shops, bars, and restaurants,
this area has plenty to offer.
A key business location or a quiet place to sit and relax,
there is plenty to see and do.
Well, we've come to the end of our video tour
of Canary Wharf and Docklands.
If you know of any fun places we've missed,
make sure you post a comment in the comment section below.
And if you're coming to London,
be sure to visit our website at nyhabitat.com
and book a vacation rental or furnished apartment
with New York Habitat.
You'll find furnished apartments all over London.
I'm David Hill with New York Habitat.
Thank you for watching our video tour
and we hope to see you soon in London.